NETFLIX オリジナルシリーズ
〜
（一樹(かずき)）これがアルサス？
This is ALSUS?
（雄哉(ゆうや)）
そうだ 多目的手術装置アルサス
Yes, the multipurpose
surgical installation, ALSUS.
だが マターの本体がアルサスを
のみ込んでしまっている
However, the body
of the Matter has engulfed it.
（アイコ）
じゃあ
この大きい塊みたいなのが…
So, this giant blob of stuff is...
（雄哉）
そう バーストを起こした
君の人工生体の体
That's right. It's your artificial body
that caused the Burst.
ハァ
ハッ
（一樹）アイコちゃん！
Aiko!
Aiko Tachibana! I'm sorry I took so long!
橘(たちばな)アイコ！ 待たせてすまない
僕だ 由良俊英(ゆらとしひで)だ
It's me, Toshihide Yura!
（一樹）
く… 首が腹に突き刺さってる
The head's buried in the stomach!
Her body turned to Matter,
and is looking for its own brain.
（雄哉）
マター化した体が
自分の脳を探し求めた結果だろう
（２人）おっ
（２人）あっ！
これから君たちの脳を
本当の体に戻す
I'll return your brains
to their proper bodies now.
聞こえるか？
Can you hear me?
あっ　うっ…
あっ…
アイコちゃん！
Aiko!
ねえ もう一度 声 聞かせて
Hey! Let me hear your voice again!
（橘アイコ）あ… あ…
どうして こんなことに
How did this happen?
ん？
（一樹）ヤバい 囲まれた！
（アイコ）え？
We're surrounded!
（２人）え？
（楓(かえで)）間に合った！
We made it!
Holy shit!
（相模(さがみ)）これは…
（遙香(はるか)）これが本体？
Is this her body?
（相模）マジかよ
Are you serious?
（白石(しらいし)）アイコちゃん あなた…
Aiko, are you going to...?
You are, aren't you?
（楓）決めたんだな
はい
Yes.
皆さん ありがとう
Thank you, everyone.
（一樹）くっ
（相模）
あんたの覚悟は 確かに受け止めた
If that's your decision, we accept it.
ん…
急げ！ 神崎(かんざき)
Hurry, Kanzaki!
神崎君 ありがとう
Thank you, Kanzaki.
私を生み出してくれて
For creating me,
私が私になれる場所を
見つけてくれて
and for finding the place
where I could be myself.
神崎君？
Kanzaki?
（一樹）どうしたんだ！ 神崎
What are you doing?
このミッションが成功したら
If this mission succeeded,
僕は君とともに
僕自身を終わらせるつもりでいた
I was going to end my own life
along with yours.
あ…
（一樹）ん？
（白石）あっ…
アンチ･セルアセンブラ？
An Anti-Cell Assembler.
（遙香）
バーストを…
マターを消滅させるために
It was what he intended
to inject Aiko with to end the Burst.
アイコちゃんに投与するはずの…
君を死なせたくない
I don't want to kill you.
はっ…
（相模）手術を中止するのか？
You won't do the surgery?
（雄哉）
いや 手術は必ず成功させる
No, I promise the surgery
will be a success.
（２人）え？
（雄哉）
僕は… 由良俊英は
すべてを元へと帰すことで
I, Toshihide Yura, was going to
take responsibility for what I had done
無に戻すことで
責を果たそうとした
by returning everything to the way it was.
そのために
君をここまで連れてきた
That's why I brought you here.
そのつもりだった
That was my intention.
However,
けれど
君は 自分が本物の
橘アイコでないことを受け止め
you accepted the fact
that you're not the real Aiko Tachibana.
それでもなお
Nonetheless,
本物の彼女と君自身にとって
最善の道を探し 決断をした
you searched for the best path
for the real Aiko and you, and took it.
その決断は偽物じゃない
That's no decision
a fake human could make.
あっ…
（雄哉）君は僕が作り出した
ウソなんかじゃなかった
When I made you, you were not fake.
この世に生まれた瞬間から
君は本物の君なんだ
From the moment you were born,
you were the real you.
そんな君を
なかったことになんかできない
I cannot deny that you ever existed.
僕は君を死なせない
I won't let you die.
はっ…
（一同）あ…
（雄哉）
君が君として生きられる世界を
僕の手で作り出す
I myself will build a world
where you can live.
それが僕の果たすべき
本当の贖罪(しょくざい)だ
That is the only way
to atone for what I've done.
（白石）
でも体がマター化したままで
そんなこと 本当にできると？
But, can you do that
while her body is Matter?
やってみせる
I will!
君が
背負おうとしてくれているものを
I'll share the burden
that you're about to bear.
僕も背負う
背負わせてほしい
If you'll let me.
神崎君
Kanzaki...
僕の手で君の体を
元の姿にしてみせる
By my own hand,
I will return your body to the way it was.
（ドン！）
（一同）あっ！
（一同）くっ！
（遙香）
オリジナルのアイコちゃんの意識が
マターを押さえきれなくなってる
The original Aiko's consciousness
can't hold back the Matter.
（白石）
彼女の意識が完全に消滅したら
If she completely loses consciousness,
手術をしても元のアイコちゃんに
戻せなくなってしまうわ
even completing the surgery
won't get her back!
アイコ君！
早く私のところに帰らないと
Aiko! If you don't hurry up
and come back to me,
柚葉(ゆずは)を
目覚めさせられないじゃないか！
I'll never be able to wake up Yuzuha!
（楓）やらせるかって！
I won't let you!
（雄哉）
伊佐津さん 聞こえますか？
Can you hear me, Isazu?
柚葉ちゃんの意識は
Yuzuha's consciousness is seeking
to return to her body!
帰る体を見つけ出せずに
さまよっているんです
If you cut the link
between her and her duplicate bodies--
彼女と彼女のマター化した
複製体とのリンクを解除すれば…
（伊佐津）
黙れ！ 由良俊英
Silence, Toshihide Yura!
柚葉のことは
私が誰よりもよく分かっている！
I know more about Yuzuha than anyone else!
PULSE
BLOOD PRESSURE
（佐保(さほ)）もうすぐよ 柚葉ちゃん
It won't be long now, Yuzuha.
あっ…
はっ！
ひぃ！
キュキュ
（アイコ）え？
（グミ）キュイ
（アイコ）グミ？
Gummi!
（雄哉）
前に君がマターに襲われたときも
When the Matter attacked you before,
Gummi surrounded and protected you.
グミが包んで守ってくれていた
（雄哉）安心しろ
（アイコ）うん
-Don't worry.
-Okay.
I'm closing the capsule.
カプセルを閉じる
次に会うときは
私 マターの体なんだよね？
The next time we meet,
I'll be in the Matter, right?
大丈夫 必ず僕が守る
Don't worry. I swear to protect you.
（竹原(たけはら)）
それは…
Those are...
Yuzuha's duplicate bodies.
They didn't turn to Matter!
マター化を免れていた
柚葉ちゃんの複製体！
Yuzuha, let me borrow your sisters
for a while.
柚葉 しばらく
お前の妹たちを貸しておくれ
さあ つなげるよ 娘たち
Okay, I'll link to you now, my daughters.
私の脳と１つになろう
Become one with my mind.
行っておいで
Go to her.
アイコ君の元へ
Go to Aiko.
だ… 誰か！
Someone, help us!
（相模）なんだ？ 動きが止まった
What? They stopped moving.
あっ！
（楓）来た！
（遙香）人型？
-Look!
-Human forms!
They're different!
（白石）何か違う！
（楓）人型っていうか 人じゃん！
Those aren't human forms. They're humans!
柚葉ちゃんの複製体
They're Yuzuha's duplicate bodies.
故意にマター化させたのか
Were they turned to Matter on purpose?
Dammit, Isazu!
くっ 伊佐津さん！
（楓）これ 撃っていいの？
Is it okay to shoot these?
大丈夫だ
その複製体に意識はない
Yes!
Those duplicate aren't conscious.
（伊佐津）
柚葉 お前は
お父さんが必ず 必ず…
Yuzuha, I swear I will bring you back.
脳交換術式を開始する
Commencing brain transfer surgery.
（黒瀬(くろせ)）鍵穴？
A keyhole?
（小春(こはる)）
柚葉ちゃんの部屋のドア
電子ロックじゃない
The lock on Yuzuha's room
isn't electronic.
ハッキングじゃ開けられないわ
I can't hack it open.
（黒瀬）ああ…
医局の誰かを巻き込むしかないか
We'll need someone
from the medical staff.
あっ？
（黒瀬）竹原！
Takehara!
黒瀬先生…
Dr. Kurose...
（雄哉）頭髪 頭皮を除去
Removing hair and scalp.
Yuzuha...
（伊佐津の思念）
柚葉 柚葉…
（柚葉の思念）
お願い やめて お父さん！
Please stop, Dad!
（伊佐津の思念）
心配いらないよ もうすぐだから
Don't worry. It won't be long now.
（楓）ウソ！ アイコの体に？
They're entering Aiko!
（遙香）本体を攻撃？
Are they attacking her body?
弾が もう！
I'm out of bullets!
あっ…マズいわ！
This is bad!
伊佐津さん！
Isazu!
（相模）何しやがる！
How dare you!
やめてくれ！ 伊佐津さん
Stop it, Isazu!
How's this?
（伊佐津）どうだ？
（雄哉）くっ
If you can't return the duplicate brain
to this body,
この本体に
複製体の脳が戻らなければ
you'll never accomplish your objective!
貴様のもくろみは
果たされることはない！
伊佐津さん あなたは！
Damn you, Isazu!
（伊佐津）
今なら まだ間に合う
It's not too late to turn back.
アイコ君を今の姿のまま
返したまえ
Give Aiko to me as she is now!
（雄哉）頭蓋軟化処置
Softening the skull.
あっ…
黒瀬先生 どうして？
Why are you here, Dr. Kurose?
柚葉ちゃんを助けたい
I want to save Yuzuha.
え？
What?
（伊佐津）
あああああ！
分かってきた！ これはいい
I can see it now! This is amazing!
うおおおお！
複製体が制御されてる
マズい！
He's controlling the duplicate body! Damn!
皆さん！ あの頭部を
頭を狙ってください！
Everyone! Fire at the head of that thing!
-Wilco!
（一同）ウィルコー！
（雄哉）頭蓋解放
Skull opened.
セル･アセンブラ２
止血処理 良好
Cell Assembler Two hemostasis normal.
セル･アセンブラ３
脳 延髄 眼球の摘出処置
Now for the removal of the brain,
medulla, and eyes by Cell Assembler Three.
（佐保）柚葉ちゃんが目覚める？
Yuzuha will wake up...
if we cut her link
to the duplicate bodies?
複製体とのリンクを解除すれば
うん
Yes.
（佐保）あっ…
CONNECTING
（楓）アイコの体じゃ撃てないよ！
I can't shoot Aiko's body!
ぐはっ！
（遙香）楓！
Kaede!
うっ！
（一樹）アイコちゃん
Aiko!
（伊佐津）
動く！ 動くぞ！
I'll move! I'm going to move!
My body can go anywhere!
私の体が どこまでも広がる！
（白石）うっ！
Shit!
（楓）こんの！
うっ！
（楓）相模！
Sagami!
相模！
うっ　ひっ
（雄哉）脳神経摘出
Cranial nerves extracted.
脳波正常
身体部分もバイタル安定
Brain waves normal. Body vitals stable.
（楓）えい！
えい！ くそ！
Damn it!
こっちはいい！
お前は神崎を守れ！
Forget about me! Protect Kanzaki!
（楓）あっ！
あっ…
（一樹）くそ！
Damn it!
（伊佐津）
人の体のなんと不便なこと
The human body is such an inconvenience!
（雄哉）
脳組織を頭蓋内定位置に固定
The brain is properly affixed
within the skull.
脳神経系 脈管系の接合作業に入る
Commencing connection
of nervous and vascular systems.
（伊佐津）
非力なこと！
It's so powerless!
（白石）
それはアンチ･セルアセンブラ！
That's the Anti-Cell Assembler!
（遙香）
でもアンプル 弾丸用じゃない
銃では撃ち出せないわ
But that vial isn't for shooting.
We can't fire it with a gun!
くっ それなら…
In that case...
（一樹）えい！
くっ！ うっ！
楓！ ここを撃ち抜け！
Kaede! Shoot into here!
え？
こいつの体内で
Disperse the Anti-Cell Assembler
inside its body!
アンチ･セルアセンブラを
四散させろ！
（相模）なに！
（楓）えっ！
-What?
（楓）でも そんなことしたら…
But, if I do that...
知ってるだろ！
この腕は俺の腕じゃない
You know this isn't my real arm!
あっ！
うっ
（楓）いくよ
（一樹）おう
-Here it goes!
-Do it!
（一樹）くっ！
（一樹）続けろ
Keep it up!
あっ！ うっ
（伊佐津）
うう… 柚葉…
Yuzuha...
柚葉…
あっ　やった？
Did we do it?
（柚葉の思念）
お父さん どうしたの？ お父さん！
Dad? What's wrong? Dad?
お父さん！
Dad!
あっ　柚葉ちゃん！
Yuzuha!
（一同）あっ！
（雄哉）神経系融合確認
Confirming neural fusion.
頭蓋閉鎖
頭皮毛髪 再生課程
Skull closed. Scalp and hair regenerated.
DELINKING SUCCESSFUL
ハア…
複製体とのリンクを切断
バイタルにも異常なしだ
The link to the duplicate bodies
is severed. Vitals are normal.
柚葉ちゃん？
Yuzuha?
あっ…
術式終了
Surgery complete.
ハア…
（アイコ）終わったの？
Is it over?
本当の自分の体に戻れたの？
Have both Aiko and I been returned
to our own bodies?
アイコも私も
ああ
Yes.
よかった
Thank goodness.
（一樹）くっ…
（せきこみ）
（アイコ）
今 お母さんと亮太(りょうた)を
I've just released Mom and Ryota
from the cocoon.
繭から解放しました
誰か２人を…
Someone go help them.
（一同）あっ…
（雄哉）
誰か行ってもらえませんか？
場所を共有します
Can someone see to them?
I'll share their position.
（相模）お… おう！ 楓
Roger! Kaede.
（楓）あっ うん
Okay!
（３人）あ…
（橘アイコ）由良先生
Dr. Yura.
私 元に戻ったんですか？
Am I back to normal?
Yes.
うん
（一樹）
本当に
あのアイコちゃんじゃないのか？
Is that really the other Aiko?
はじめまして
Nice to meet you.
（一同）あっ…
ねえ 先生 あの子は？
Doctor, what about the other girl?
あっ！
（アイコ）よかった
Thank goodness.
戻れたのね
You're back.
（一同）え？
（一樹）
アイコちゃん アイコちゃん！
Aiko!
（橘アイコ）
ねえ 返事して！ お願い！
Hey! Answer! Please!
Aiko!
（一樹）アイコちゃん！
はっ！ 橘！
Tachibana!
ねえ！ ねえ！
Come on!
（遙香）ダメだったってこと？
It didn't work?
（白石）せっかくここまで…
She came all this way...
アイコ…
Aiko...
どうして どうして
Why?
You did it for Mom, for Ryota,
お母さんのために 亮太のために
私のために
for me...
頑張ってくれたのに
You did so much for us.
（一樹）くっ…
（雄哉）アイコ…
Aiko...
（鼓動）
あっ
（一同）あっ！
（一同）あっ…
（一樹）何だ？
What's that?
（一同）あっ！
（雄哉）これもマターなのか？
Is that Matter, too?
（アイコ）ゴホッ ゴホッ…
（一同）え？
（一樹）アイコちゃん？
Aiko?
あれ？ みんな
What? Why are you...
あれ？ 私…
What? I'm...
わっ！
（グミ）キュイ
（アイコ）え？
グミ？
Gummi?
（遙香）
体の再構成？ 一体どうやって？
Her body was regenerated? But how?
グミがアイコの生体情報を
保存していた？
Did Gummi have a copy of Aiko's body data?
I'm... I'm...
私… 私…
夢じゃない
I'm not dreaming?
（橘アイコ）うん
That's right.
It hurts!
（アイコ）あたっ
夢じゃない
It's not a dream!
Thank goodness.
（橘アイコ）よかった
ホントによかった
I'm so happy.
こいつは…
I can't believe it.
お父さんに１本 取られた
Her dad was the one who saved her.
（一樹）ハア〜！
（アイコ）白石さん
Shiraishi.
（一樹）ハハハッ！
But, why?
（橘アイコ）どうして？
お母さんや亮太には
私がちゃんと説明するよ
I'll explain everything to Mom and Ryota.
絶対 分かってくれる
They'll understand.
だから４人で 一緒に暮らそう
I want the four of us to live together.
違うの 元に戻してあげたいの
No. I want to return everything to normal.
お父さんのこと バーストのこと
Since you had to go through so much,
losing your father,
大変なこと いろいろあったから
and the Burst,
これからは お母さんと亮太には
I want you, Mom, and Ryota
to live a peaceful life together.
あなたと一緒に
穏やかに過ごしてほしいの
でも…
But...
（アイコ）お願い
Please.
でも！
But!
私の気持ち あなたは知ってるはず
I think you understand how I feel.
あっ…
うれしいよ　ありがとう アイコ
That makes me happy.
Thank you, Aiko.
じゃあ！ じゃあ せめて！
Then, you can at least...
（母）ありがとうございます
（亮太）ありがとう
-Thank you.
-Thanks!
（アイコ）お母さん 亮太
Mom! Ryota!
（母）アイコ！
（亮太）姉ちゃん！
-Aiko!
大丈夫？ ２人とも
Are you two all right?
体がフラフラする
I feel a little lightheaded.
あなたのほうこそ 大丈夫なの？
I was so worried. Are you okay?
Yes.
うん
そう よかった
Really? Thank goodness.
ありがとうね アイコ
Thank you, Aiko.
I'm hungry.
腹 減った
すぐに病院に運んでもらうからね
They'll get you to a hospital soon.
ちゃんと診てもらって
ちゃんと食べて ちゃんと寝よう
Get checked out, eat something,
and get some sleep.
こうして元気になったアイコ
I only wish that your father
お父さんにも見せてあげたかった
could see you doing so well.
うん
Yes.
お父さんも
たくさん守ってくれたよ
Dad protected me a lot, too.
（母）そうだ
Oh, that's right. I need to say thank you
to everyone that came with you.
一緒に来てくださった皆さんにも
お礼言わないとね
（亮太）
あの人たち 何？
超かっこいいんだけど
Who are those guys? They're totally cool!
（アイコ）
一緒に助けに来てくれたの
They came with me to save you.
お姉ちゃんの仲間よ
They're my friends.
仲間？ 何それ？
姉ちゃん すげえ
Your friends? No way!
You're awesome, Aiko!
（アイコ）あっ…
ああ〜
姉ちゃん？
Aiko?
アイコ？
よかった ２人とも無事で
I'm so glad you're both okay.
生きててくれて ありがとう
Thank goodness you're alive.
ちょっと着替えてくるね
I'm going to go change.
（楓）くっ
（グミ）キュキュキュ キュウ
（白石）このあと どこへ行くの？
Where will you go after this?
これから考えます
I'll have to think about it.
きっと あるはずだから
君が存在してもいい世界が
I know there is a world
where you can exist. I'm sure of it.
もし ないなら
If there isn't...
僕が作る
I'll make it.
Okay.
うん
あっ…
白石さん ありがとうございました
Shiraishi, thank you for everything.
アイコ…
Aiko...
（地響き）
（一同）あっ…！
（男１）結晶化して崩落？
（男２）何だ？
-Crystallized and collapsed?
-What?
（男１）
いえ プライマリー･ポイントの
周囲のマターが…
The Matter around Primary Point
has collapsed.
-I'm here to pick you up, Director.
-The whole thing?
（堀(ほり)）お迎えに上がりました 局長
（柚葉）お父さん
Dad...
Dad?
お父さん…
（橘アイコ）また一緒だね
We're together again.
How many times have you
and I been in the same class?
（菜穂(なほ)）
もうさ アイコと
おんなじクラスって何回目？
Hey, Ryota! Lend us a hand!
（橘アイコ）
ちょっと亮太！
あんたも手伝いなさいよ
It hurts!
いっ！ 痛っ
（母）大丈夫？
Are you okay?
（橘アイコ）大丈夫 大丈夫
It's fine. I'm fine.
もう よそ見するから
Watch what you're doing.
Go on. Wash it.
はい ちゃんと洗って
My sister is such a klutz!
（亮太）姉ちゃん ドジ！
（橘アイコ）
亮太！
そんなとこにボール置かない！
Ryota! Don't leave your ball there!
（佐保）
まずは この項とこの項を
展開してみて
First, expand these two equations.
（竹原）柚葉ちゃん
Yuzuha!
由良先生からの贈り物だ
It's a gift from Dr. Yura.
（雄哉）
大丈夫だ 脳も体も異常なし
You're fine.
Your mind and body are normal.
Your next checkup will be...
じゃあ 次の定期健診は…
Summer vacation.
It has been a year since it all happened.
（アイコ）
夏休み
あれから１年になるんだね
That's right.
（雄哉）
そうだな
（アイコ）
会いたいな あの子に みんなに
I really want to meet her again,
and everyone else.
（雄哉）
そのときが来たら
The time will come.
（アイコ）
うん そのときが来たら
Yes, when the time comes.
（グミ）
キュイ
I'm here. Let's go.
（小春）お待たせ！ さあ 行こう
（アイコ）
こうして 今日も１つ
自分だけの思い出が重なっていく
This is another day for me
to make memories that are all my own.
YUBARI SHIMIZUSAWA HIGH
（教師）転校生を紹介するぞ
We have a new transfer student.
はじめまして 私の名前は…
It's nice to meet you. My name is...
Subtitle translation by Brian Athey
&lrm;〜